CLOUD ARCHITECT

Enterprise Architecture * Strategic Planning * Technology Direction, Design/Delivery & Implementation

A versatile technology strategist with a successful history of delivering large scale and transformative business solutions. A hands-on leader with a passion for innovating and team building. Exceptional ability to anticipated technology hypes. Excellent critical thinker for solving business problems. Outstanding interpersonal and communication skills and style that is open and effective with executives, customers, and teams. Expert knowledge of cost-effective IT solutions, operations, and data privacy.

- Expert in Enterprise and Infrastructure Architecture
- Google Certifed Cloud Professional Architect
- Substantial experience with cloud implementation
 - Public and private clouds(IaaS) GCP, AWS and OpenStack
 - Microservices(PaaS) Openshift, Rancher based on kubernetes
- Agile and Waterfall Methodologies, DevOps, CI/CD
- Relationship management internal, client, vendor
- Excellent communication, facilitation and leadership skills
- Strong analytical abilities, critical thinking
- Full lifecycle project management
- IT Vision and Trends Specialist

EXPERIENCE

CTO (CHIEF TECHNOLOGY OFFICER)

Khallagh Borhan

2015 - MARCH 2019

- Led the complete turnaround of the Technology department through talent acquisition and management Based on a Long-Term vision to become the prominent IT Infrastructure provider for Large-scale OTT and social media services in the country.
- Recruited and managed a team of more than 100 IT professionals to design, build and operate a large scale- nationwide IT and Telecom infrastructure.
- Provided leadership, implementation and support to 4 (laaS, CDN, OTT, PaaS) distinctive business lines within the organization
- Provided leadership and engineering expertise on OpenShift for introducing new products
- Built an Enterprise managed-services team to operate the network with the highest KPI/SLA in the country and implemented ITIL for all of the vital services lifecycles.
- Played a critical role in meeting with investors to obtain funding.
- Performed annual budget planning and reporting to the board of directors.

- After four years from only 3 IT employees and 4 Servers, headed the technical department to scale-up to 100 employees and around 22000 cores of Computing power and Petabytes of object and block-storage beginning to achieve the role of Biggest privately-owned cloud provider in the country. and the biggest CDN and Streaming solutions in the region.
- Wrote the vision and completed the projects which accomplished :

Cloud PaaS

- Integrate and configure different monitoring and management tools like Dynatrace, Prometheus to collect the real-time status of OpenShift Cluster.
- Design and build a reliable and scalable cloud-native platform using the Red Hat OpenShift Container Platform.
- Perform functional testing for multi-tier failover.

Cloud laaS

- Biggest Privately owned Compute cloud in the region. Full-service catalogue of Hybrid cloud from Vmware to OpenStack
- Establish methods to operate on support the Openstack for end customers(Based on ITIL best practices)

■ CDN

- Prominent CDN in Region with more than 14 Nodes in Major Telcos.
- More than 120 Gbs of Throughput.
- Developed Technology for a CDN solution
- Created the support mechanism and FO/BO AND NOC teams based on ITIL Best Practices.

■ SDN/NFV

- Established a VCPE solution as POC for the biggest telecom company in the country for their 5G network
- Worked on NFV project for MCI's IoT platform
- Other developed and managed projects :
 - OVP (Online Video Platform):
 - Vidad (Video Advertising Platform Based on VAST and VPAID standards)
 - Live streaming: Wowza, Mist server, Red5 Media server
 - IPTV MW

IPTV PROJECT MANAGER

2012 - 2015

Faragostaresh

- IPTV-MW solutions with over 24 linear channels and 10k VODs.
- Designed and set up On-line TV and Radio Stations studio for IPTV Solutions.
- Provided Audio and Video compression file systems for my clients to upload to client's websites.
- Installed and maintained the web-servers and hosting solutions for the company
- Managed streaming solutions based on Wowza and Mist server
- Integrated Banking standards for core e-shopping products

LINUX SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

2011 - 2012

Zentex

- Provided Linux technical support and prepared technical documentation for check-in verification
- Linux System and Services Administration (DNS-Hosting Services-Email Services-Billing services-Monitoring services,...)
- Performed Linux administration and data migration activities.
- Installed and configurated of VPN, Proxy and Firewall (PfSense).
- VMware Understanding of VMware Concepts) ESX Host, Virtual Machines) and the ability to access Virtual Machines through Virtual Center.

IT CONSULTANT 2008-2016

MCI

- Coordinated with Companies Executives and Deputy ministers to evaluate and improve software and hardware interfaces.
- Wrote Request for proposals (RFP) on IT sectors for OIL-companies like PetroPars and Telcos like MCI
- Created LOM and LOP for IT projects.

CCO-WAN CONTRACTOR

2007-2008

ITI

- Established a contract with TCl for 600 G.shdsl ports to be part of Customer care offices for national gas cards project.
- Used Cisco, Huawei and Tellabs products in the process of initializing the network

NETWORK ASSISTANT & ADMINISTRATOR

2006-2007

Ashna secure

- Resolved WAN and LAN connectivity issues, public and private IP assignments, and DNS changes.
- Wrote and collected documentation and maintain the Standard Operating Procedures, knowledge base, and FAQs

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

Various Freelance jobs and contracts for IT services

EDUCATION

Studied Computer Engineering at Sharif University

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

• Professional Cloud Architect

Google

o Certification ID: GsKWzG

HONOUR & AWARD

• Bronze Medal in National Computer Olympiad June-2006